<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Palash Karmore</title>
    <description>A blog for my projects.</description>
    <link>https://palash247.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://palash247.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 08:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 08:21:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>100 days of ML code logs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My everyday progress logs of the #100daysofMLCode challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;date-27072018&quot;&gt;Date: 27/07/2018:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the day, I revisited the derivation for the back-propagation algorithm. I struggle with writing differential equations for matrices. The only way I could come up with the proper differentiation is by matching the dimensions of the matrices. I don’t know if it’s the correct way of doing Linear Algebra-Calculus, but for now, it is working for me. For reference, I’ve used the first course of Andrew Ng’s Deep Learning specialization from Coursera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;date-28072018&quot;&gt;Date: 28/07/2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read an article by Randal J. Barnes about Matrix Differentiation. I found it interesting and now I know how to backpropagate without matching the dimensions of the matrices involved in the differentiation. Then I went back to the maths of forwarding and backward propagation of Deep-L layer neural network from Andrew Ng’s Deep Learning course. Now I feel a little more confident about the derivation and I hope I would not forget it soon. I think I should make flashcards about this real soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;date-29072018&quot;&gt;Date: 29/07/2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloaded assignments from Coursera as they don’t let you redo your assignments after completing the certifications. Now, I have a copy of every ipython notebook assignments of Deep Learning course. I don’t know if its illegal, but I find it helpful to solve problems while revising, so I will keep them. For the day, I’ve completed the Deep-L layer NN assignment from the first course of Deep Learning Specialization. And there’s one more project I am working on which allows you to schedule a message on a message platform. Today, I’ve explored different third-party APIs to automate message sending on WhatsApp and then I went with Selenium web driver as it appears to all the third party APIs are doing it the same way. I’ve successfully shared text message through Selenium but then I had to grant the access permission every time I ran the application which sucks. I found solutions for it and I’ve tried some with no luck I will try more soon. Also, I learned how to set up a VNC server on a cheap digital ocean droplet which will help me with this selenium automation. Another thing is I am trying to wake up at 4 am but I am struggling with going to sleep early. I will keep on trying though. That’s it for the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;date-30072018&quot;&gt;Date: 30/07/2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I struggled to wake up at 4 am again. Next day I will try harder. For the day, I’ve configured Twilio with the chatbot I am building for my company. Before that, I was engaged in the generating more stories (conversation flows) for the bot to tackle mistakes it was doing. Before that when I woke up at 6 am I went through some modular way to implement fully connected NN with any architecture. Tomorrow I will try a little harder to wake up at 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;date-31072018&quot;&gt;Date: 31/07/2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The struggle with the early waking up is still on. In the morning I revised L1, L2 Regularization, Dropout for reducing over-fitting and for the rest of the day I was stuck with the [Asterisk][Asterisk] configuration for setting up a [Duplex like AI agent][Duplex like AI agent]. I am learning a way to set up packages so that a user can call an AI agent and have a meaningful conversation with it.
[Asterisk]:https://www.asterisk.org/
[Duplex like AI agent]:https://medium.com/rasa-blog/building-your-own-duplex-ai-agent-using-rasa-and-twilio-bbd23c80ed30
### Date: 01/08/2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, woke up at 4 am. Implemented He Initialization to tackle the problem of vanishing/exploding gradients in NNs, then L2 and Dropout to perform regularization and reduce over-fitting and then implemented Gradient Check to validate the implementation of back-propagation. In the office, I’ve successfully integrated Twilio’s Programmable Voice &amp;amp; Speech recognition APIs with Rasa chatbot. I am really excited about this project and I will make a tutorial for it real soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;date-30102018&quot;&gt;Date: 30/10/2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#### Slept: 11:30 pm
#### Woke up: 5:10 am&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting the challenge again. I was expecting too much from myself which resulted in me being depressed and guilty of not doing everything that is possible. I’ve stopped smoking a month ago and also started working out at least 6 days a weak. Recently, I am feeling a little better about myself and hence I want to continue this challenge from where I left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning from previous mistakes, I’ve changed the definition of a successful day. It’s only minimum 1 hour of focused work on machine learning which makes up the successful day. Anything extra would be a bonus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrote stories for a chatbot (office work). Read about &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/these-tools-will-help-you-write-clean-code-da4b5401f68e&quot;&gt;how to manage multiple git/bitbucket SSH keys on a single machine&lt;/a&gt;. And posted on the blog again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s target:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primary:
1. Complete the chatbot
2. Read at least two chapters of Pandas for data analysis.
3. Run 2 km
4. Go to Gym
5. Complete the backlog reprots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May be:
5. Find a way to integrate any type of task planner in the jekyll theme.
6. Integrate it with current theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vT7iaGro_WSdFFE2M1ttT_x6Q9vp_p8I1lgJQ2Wl5OSukFrXgKmoyPPSFjDCyCZ23MtSgFWeVdhetBp/pubhtml?widget=true&amp;amp;headers=false&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://palash247.github.io/articles/2018-07/100-days-of-ML-code-logs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://palash247.github.io/articles/2018-07/100-days-of-ML-code-logs</guid>
        
        
        <category>logs</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
